https://www.tawk.to/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy – tawk.to
Beta Release: 100% Free Knowledge Base Software now live!
Blog
Why Free?
Blog
Why Free?
Log in
Sign Up Free
Privacy Policy
Updated 20 February 2020
Your privacy is important to us at tawk.to. Here is how your Privacy is maintained :
We don’t request access to you personal information unless we truly need it to provide the service eg: Your gender or income levels are irrelevant to us, so we don’t ask you for that information.
We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
Below is our privacy policy which adhere to those principles :
If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data please initiate a chat with us, or send us an email at any time.
Tawk.to operates a web application and corresponding mobile apps (on http://www.tawk.to). It is tawk.to’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our services.
Website Visitors
Like most internet-service operators, tawk.to collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers, apps and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, geographical location, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. tawk.to’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how tawk.to’s visitors use its services, and to provide tawk.to users the ability to understand how their visitors use their services. From time to time, tawk.to may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its services.
tawk.to also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for users that use the services and visitors.
Gathering and Use of Personally-Identifying Information
Certain visitors to tawk.to’s websites and users of tawk.to’s apps choose to interact with tawk.to in ways that require tawk.to to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that tawk.to gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask users of our app to provide an email address. In each case, tawk.to collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with tawk.to. tawk.to does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.
Additionally, if: (a) you are established in the European Economic Area (EEA); (b) you provide goods or services to customers in the EEA; or (c) you are otherwise subject to the requirements of the EU General Data Protection Regulation, tawk.to’s collection and use of personal information of any European residents is also subject to our Data Processing Addendum.
Permitted Purposes:
We may use the information we collect about you (including personal information, to the extent applicable) for a variety of purposes, including to (a) provide, operate, maintain, improve, and promote the tawk.to Service; (b) enable you to access and use the tawk.to Service; (c) process and complete transactions; (d) provide customer service and support and send you related notices; (e) send promotional communications; (f) process and deliver contest or sweepstakes entries and rewards; (g) monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with the tawk.to Service and for marketing or advertising purposes; (h) monitor and assess compliance with our policies and standards; and (i) for other purposes for which we obtain your consent. With regard to newsletters, updates and other general communications, we will – where legally required – only provide you with such information if you have opted in. You have the opportunity to opt out of receiving such communications at any time.
Legal Basis for Processing (EEA only):
If you are an individual from the European Economic Area (EEA),  we use your personal data, we may process your personal data on one or more of the following legal grounds: (i) because processing is necessary to perform a contract with you, such as to deliver the tawk.to Service; (ii) to comply with our legal obligations; (iii) because processing is necessary for purposes of our legitimate interest or those of any third party recipients that receive your personal data, provided that such interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.  We may also process your data based on your consent where you have expressly given that to us.
Retention Period:
We will retain your personal information for as long as is needed to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. For personal information that we process on behalf of our customers, we will retain such personal information in accordance with the terms of our agreement with them, subject to applicable law.
Types of personal data we collect and use
We will only process personal data in ways that are compatible with the purpose we collected it for, or for the purposes you later authorize. Before we use your personal data for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose we collected it for or that you later authorized, we will provide you with the opportunity to opt-out. We maintain reasonable procedures to help ensure that personal data we collect and use is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current.
Data transfers to third parties
For a list of all current third parties used by tawk.to please refer to the following link on our web site: http://www.tawk.to/data-protection/sub-processors/.  The purposes for which the company engages these selected third parties is in accordance with providing the services offered by tawk.to including; data and email hosting, cloud analytics and communications services, as well as application distribution. A list of our current third party service providers and sub-processors that are certified with ITA Privacy Shield frameworks is provided below.
Agents, consultants and service providers: We may share your personal data with our contractors and service providers who process personal data on our behalf to perform certain business-related functions. These companies include database service providers, backup and disaster recovery service providers, email service providers and others. When we engage another company to perform such functions, we may provide them with information, including personal data, in connection with their performance of such functions.
Our Company and Affiliates: We may also share your personal data with our parent companies, subsidiaries and/or affiliates for purposes consistent with this Policy.
Business Transfers: As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, personal data may be part of the transferred assets.
Disclosures for National Security or Law Enforcement: Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your personal data in response to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
Legal Requirements: We may disclose your personal data if required to do so by law in order to (for example) respond to a subpoena or request from law enforcement, a court or a government agency, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary (a) to comply with a legal obligation, (b) to protect or defend our rights, interests or property or that of third parties, (c) to prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Services, (d) to act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Users of the Services or the public; or (e) to protect against legal liability.
Tawk.to ensures the most commercially viable selection process by which it evaluates the security, privacy and confidentiality practices of its third parties and sub-processors that may have access to or process our service data.
The company will comply with the enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) in accordance with their investigatory requirements and will comply with requests made by public authorities to meet national security enforcement requirements.
In cases of onward transfers of data, received pursuant to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, tawk.to. is potentially liable.
ITA Privacy Shield Certified Third Parties
Tawk.to Third Party/Sub-processors
ITA Privacy Shield Privacy Policy Certification
Company
Purpose
Framework(s)
Status
Amazon Web Services (AWS), USA, Ireland
Data Hosting
EU-U.S. Privacy Shield
Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield
Active
Digital Ocean, USA
Data Hosting, MTA Email Hosting
Security
We maintain reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction in accordance with the Privacy Shield.
Access Rights
In general, when processing personal data to provide our services, we do so only on behalf of our customers and in accordance with their instructions. This means that if you wish to access any personal data we process on behalf of a tawk.to customer and request that we correct, amend, delete it if it is inaccurate or processed in violation of Privacy Shield, you should contact that customer with your request. We will then help them to fulfill that request in accordance with their instructions.
Where we process personal data collected via our website or via our services for our own account management, billing or marketing purposes, you may have the right to access personal data that we hold about you and request that we correct, amend, delete it if it is inaccurate or processed in violation of Privacy Shield. These access rights may not apply in some cases, including where providing access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances or where it would violate the rights of someone other than the individual requesting access. If you would like to request access to, correction, amendment, or deletion of your personal data, you can submit a written request to the contact information provided below. We may request specific information from you to confirm your identity. In some circumstances, we may charge a reasonable fee for access to your information.
Your Data, Your Choice
You may choose to change personal data or cancel an account by contacting us using the contact details below. You can also unsubscribe from our marketing communications by following the instructions or unsubscribe mechanism in the e-mail message.
Questions or complaints
You can direct any questions or complaints about the use or disclosure of your personal data to us at compliance@tawk.to. We will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints or disputes regarding the use or disclosure of personal data within 45 days of receiving your complaint.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact the JAMS, our third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge). To find out more, go to https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield or to make a complaint directly, please use this form at https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-claim .
Binding Arbitration
You may have the option to select binding arbitration for the resolution of your complaint under certain circumstances, provided you have taken the following steps: (1) raised your complaint directly with us and provided us the opportunity to resolve the issue; (2) made use of the independent dispute resolution mechanism identified above; and (3) raised the issue through the relevant data protection authority and allowed the US Department of Commerce an opportunity to resolve the complaint at no cost to you. To find out more about the Privacy Shield’s binding arbitration scheme please see www.privacyshield.gob/article?id=My-Rights-under-Privacy-Shield .
Aggregated Statistics
tawk.to may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. However, tawk.to does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.
Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information
tawk.to discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that:
(i) need to know that information in order to process it on tawk.to’s behalf or to provide services available at tawk.to’s webservices, and
(ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using tawk.to’s webservices, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. tawk.to will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, tawk.to discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when tawk.to believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of tawk.to, third parties or the public at large.
If you are a registered user of tawk.to and have supplied your email address, tawk.to may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with tawk.to and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. tawk.to takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.
Children’s Personal Information
We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the tawk.to Service. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through the tawk.to Service without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us through the Websites or Services, please contact us at privacy@tawk.to, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information.
Cookies
A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. tawk.to uses cookies to help tawk.to identify and track visitors, their usage of tawk.to website, and their website access preferences. tawk.to visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using tawk.to’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of tawk.to’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
Business Transfers
If tawk.to, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that tawk.to goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of tawk.to may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.
Ads
Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by tawk.to and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.
International Transfer of Data; EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield
We may from time to time transfer your personal information to other countries outside the United States and make it accessible to our parents, subsidiaries, affiliates and third-party service providers internationally. We will protect your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy wherever it is processed. Tawk.to has operations in the United States, Europe and Asia-Pacific and a number of remote contractors globally. Personal information may be processed in any country where a tawk.to employee or contractor accesses the tawk.to system.
Tawk. to complies with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and the United Kingdom and/or Switzerland to the United States. Tawk. to has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such information.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/
In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Tawk.to commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Tawk.to at: compliance@tawk.to
We may also process personal data our customers submit relating to individuals in the EEA via other compliance mechanisms, including data processing agreements based on the EU standard contractual clauses. A request for the tawk.to Standard Contractual Clause can be found here.
Privacy Policy Changes
Although most changes are likely to be minor, tawk.to may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in tawk.to’s sole discretion. tawk.to encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of these services after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
Contacting us
If you have questions about this policy, you can contact us at compliance@tawk.to.
Leave a Reply Cancel replyYou must be logged in to post a comment.
Get tawk.to
Web Browser
Windows
macOS
iOS & Android
Products
Live Chat
Chat Pages
About
Why Free?
Careers - Join us!
The Team
Customers
Partners
Let's tawk?
The green widget you see below this text is the tawk.to live chat widget, if you click it you will see the window maximize and you will be able to chat with the tawk.to team 24×7-365. You can add a chat widget like this on your own site, with your own custom colors, messages, size, position and language. Click the widget and give it a try!
Privacy & Terms
Report Abuse
Contact Us
Linkedin-in
Twitter
Facebook-f
Instagram
Youtube
© Copyright 2020 tawk.to, inc. All Rights Reserved. Various trademarks held by their respective owners.
×
- No payment needed, just a completely free 7 day trial!
